ALI ZAHID

SUMMARY

I am a young, ambitious worker hungry to learn and grow with international work experience, in the US and Belgium. I have run and managed a family property business for seven years.

From making my first computer at the age of eight to now learning how to program I have always been fascinated by computers. I have been learning programming through Codeacademy, Coursera and various other online resources. I enjoy learning computer programming and I am currently taking Codeacademy's full-stack engineering course. In my free time, I have been building various projects in HTML, CSS and JavaScript. I wish to take my learning to the next level through your software developer apprenticeship. I believe I will be a great candidate because I am enthusiastic and passionate about learning software development.

WORK HISTORY

Manager, 08/2017 to Current Z Properties - London

- Seven years managing a family property portfolio of five houses.
- Responsibilities as manager included: preparing the yearly tax return, hiring, and managing builders for repairs and refurbishments on the houses, acquiring new and maintaining existing tenants, dealing with tenant issues and queries, and maintaining all the certificates required for each property.
- I built positive relationships with my tenants to maintain the high standards of the company brand.
- Identified, planned, and implemented new real estate projects.
- Carried out refurbishments on the houses to increase profits by over 50% from the rent and saved the business money by building two kitchens by myself.

Camp counsellor/ Lifeguard, 06/2019 to 08/2019 Camp America/ Kennolyn Camps - Soquel California

- International experience working as a camp counsellor in America through Camp America.
- My roles were: Counsellor, lifeguard, guitar instructor, and basketball coach.
- Worked as a professionally qualified RLSS UK lifeguard.
- Participated in meetings to coordinate with other staff on the camper's progress, issues, and goal achievements.
- Prepared and submitted daily and weekly reports to keep records of campers' attendance, behaviour, and progress.
- Communicated with families to keep parents informed on their child's camp experience and address any concerns or issues.
- Implemented camp activities fostering physical, social, and emotional growth.
- Acted as a positive role model and mentor to provide campers with constructive guidance and promote healthy habits and attitudes.

Night shop assistant, 05/2022 to 09/2022 Nachtwinkel Lochristi Lo-Bravo - Belgium, Lochristi

- International experience in Belgium dealing with customers and fostering positive customer relationships.
- Stocked and maintained grocery store products.
- Maintained high standards of store presentation and hygiene.
- Prepared invoices for customers with large and special orders.

CONTACT

Address: 1 Bushey Road, London UB3 4AS

Phone: 07944588500 **Email:** alizahid98@live.co.uk **Web:** https://alizahid117.github.io./

MY GITHUB REPOSITORIES

https://github.com/AliZahid117?tab=repositories

SKILLS

- Knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- · Leadership and management skills
- · Problem-solving
- Positive people person
- Business administration and commercial awareness
- Revenue growth and brand management

EDUCATION

A-Levels, Biology, History, 09/2015 to 07/2017

Harlington School - London

- Biology C
- History C

GCSEs, 09/2012 to 07/2014 Harlington School - London

- 1 A
- 8 B's

HOBBIES AND INTEREST

- Guitar
- Programming
- Swimming